<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Surveys on Marta Kołczyńska</title>
    <link>/tags/surveys/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Surveys on Marta Kołczyńska</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018. Marta Kołczyńska</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 17:32:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/surveys/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliability of survey estimates: Participation in demonstrations</title>
      <link>/post/sdr-demonstrations-multiplets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 17:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sdr-demonstrations-multiplets/</guid>
      <description>DataDifferences within country-yearsDifferences by groupsGenderAgeUrban/rural residenceEducationSampling schemeThe growth in cross-national survey projects in the last decades leads to situations when two or more surveys are carried out in the same country and the same year but in different projects, and contain overlapping sets of survey questions. Assuming that the surveys are based on representative samples - a claim that major cross-national survey projects typically make - it could be expected that estimates from surveys carried out in the same country and year are reasonably close.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Validating survey data: Educational attainment in SDR and the OECD</title>
      <link>/post/education-sdr-oecd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 05:13:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/education-sdr-oecd/</guid>
      <description>Educational attainment dataOECD dataSDR dataCleaning and merging SDR and OECD dataResultsThe curious case of ISSP SwitzerlandConclusionAppendixwith Przemek Powałko
General population surveys with representative samples should have a similar education structure as shown by data from administrative sources, especially if survey weights are used. In this post we compare sample aggregates from 15 cross-national survey projects (including the European Social Survey, the World Values Survey and the European Values Study, and others) from the Survey Data Recycling database with educational attainment statistics from the OECD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiny app for exploring harmonized cross-national survey data (SDR v.1.0)</title>
      <link>/post/sdr-exploration-shiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 07:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sdr-exploration-shiny/</guid>
      <description>InstructionsReferences In the previous post I wrote about downloading and exploring the Survey Data Recycling (SDR), version 1.0 dataset, which consists of selected harmonized variables from 22 survey projects, 1966-2013.
The SDR project will develop a website for browsing, subsetting, downloading, and visualizing data from the SDR project. This website is currently under construction. Meanwhile, I made a Shiny app with basic functionalities of the future on-line browsing and subsetting tool (also serves as its mock-up): https://mkolczynska.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the dataset of survey datasets: Survey Data Recycling version 1.0</title>
      <link>/post/sdr-exploration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 15:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sdr-exploration/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionDownloading the SDR dataExploring SDR: availability of variables by projectExploring SDR: availability of variables with different formulationsIdentifying surveys containing selected variablesSubsetting the Master FileCountry coverage plotCombining data from different survey projects creates new opportunities for research, alas, at the cost of increased volume (obviously) and complexity of the data. The Survey Data Recycling project created a dataset with data from 22 international survey projects.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>