<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cross National Research on Marta Kołczyńska</title>
    <link>/tags/cross-national-research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cross National Research on Marta Kołczyńska</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018. Marta Kołczyńska</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 21:29:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/cross-national-research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>(In-)Consistency between international corruption indicators</title>
      <link>/post/corruption-indicators/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 21:29:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/corruption-indicators/</guid>
      <description>OverviewScatter plotsCorrelationsTrends in corruption indicators in Europe, 1990-2019OverviewMeasuring corruption is hard, especially if one is interested in having corruption indicators that are comparable across countries and over time. Arguably the most famous corruption ranking is the Corruption Perceptions Index published annually by Transparency International, but it can’t be used for over-time comparisons (cf. Transparency International 2020, p. 26).
Other corruption indicators include:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cleaning Freedom House indicators</title>
      <link>/post/cleaning-fh-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 22:08:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cleaning-fh-data/</guid>
      <description>How to clean a very untidy data set with Freedom House country ratings, saved in an Excel sheet, which violates many principles of data organization in spreadsheets described in this paper by Karl Broman and Kara Woo, but otherwise is an invaluable source of data on freedom in the world?
Data source: https://freedomhouse.org/content/freedom-world-data-and-resources
The full code used in this post is available here.
I would do this:
Read in the file,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Political trust among electoral winners and losers in Europe</title>
      <link>/post/ess-trust-institutions-electoral-winners-losers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 11:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ess-trust-institutions-electoral-winners-losers/</guid>
      <description>Winner-loser trust gap across countriesWinner-loser trust gap in PolandTrust differences across parties in PolandVoting for a party that ends up losing the election is known to be associated with lower satisfaction with democracy and trust in the parliament (cf. Martini and Quaranta 2019). How does Poland compare to other European countries? How has the winner-loser trust gap changed in Poland over time, and how have trust levels among supporters of current and former ruling parties changed in periods when they were not in government?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downloading country-level indicators on participation and economic inequality 2</title>
      <link>/post/participation-inequality-indices-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 15:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/participation-inequality-indices-2/</guid>
      <description>DataPackagesVarieties of Democracy (V-Dem): Dedicated packagePolyarchy: Semicolon delimited CSV file -&amp;gt; rioFreedom House: Excel file with by-year sheetsPolity IV: SPSS file -&amp;gt; rioDemocracy Barometer: Excel file with header in top rows -&amp;gt; rioThe Standardized World Income Inequality Database (SWIID): Plain CSV file -&amp;gt; rioWorld Bank’s World Development Indicators: Dedicated packageMerging all datasetsWriting to fileShortly after writing this post on importing datasets in different formats (CSV, XLS, XLSX, SAV) to R, I got the following comment:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downloading country-level indicators on participation and economic inequality</title>
      <link>/post/participation-inequality-indices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 13:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/participation-inequality-indices/</guid>
      <description>DataPackagesVarieties of Democracy (V-Dem): Dedicated packagePolyarchy: Semicolon delimited CSV fileFreedom House: Excel file with by-year sheetsPolity IV: SPSS fileDemocracy Barometer: Excel file with header in top rowsThe Standardized World Income Inequality Database (SWIID): Plain CSV fileWorld Bank’s World Development Indicators: Dedicated packageMerging all datasetsCountry graphsVariable graphsWriting to filewith Viktoriia Muliavka
Social and political scientists often need to put together datasets of country-level political, economic, and demographic variables with data from different sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal vs. household income in cross-national surveys</title>
      <link>/post/sdr-income-hh-personal-cor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 10:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sdr-income-hh-personal-cor/</guid>
      <description>Sample correlationsSample correlations by genderSample correlations by ageSample correlations by educationContrastConclusionOne of the reasons for the harmonization of personal income in addition to household income was to check if the two correlate highly enough to use household income as a substitute for personal income in analyses where economic status is a control variable. This would be great, because household income variables are available in 1177 surveys out of 1721 analyzed in the Survey Data Recycling dataset (SDR) version 1, while personal income only in 453 surveys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harmonizing measures of income in cross-national surveys</title>
      <link>/post/sdr-income-hh-personal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 17:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sdr-income-hh-personal/</guid>
      <description>DataNumber of response optionsItem non-responseDistributionsHarmonized target variablesNext stepswith Przemek Powałko
Individual economic status is a necessary element of almost all sociological analyses, including studies of political attitudes and behavior. To supplement the already harmonized variables in the Survey Data Recycling dataset (SDR) version 1 and for the purposes of my resesarch of the effects of education on political engagement, Przemek and I harmonized two additional variables: personal income and household income1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring the level and inequality of political participation with survey data</title>
      <link>/post/participation-inequality-ess/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 03:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/participation-inequality-ess/</guid>
      <description>Political participation in the ESSCountry levels of political participationInequality of political participationDemocracy indicatorsEconomic inequalityMatrix scatter plotsHow to measure political inequality? The Variaties of Democracy project (V-Dem) has a set of political equality indicators that capture the extent to which political power is distributed according to wealth and income, membership in a particular social group, gender or sexual orientation (cf. V-Dem Codebook v.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Age distributions in samples from cross-national survey projects</title>
      <link>/post/sdr-age-distributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 10:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sdr-age-distributions/</guid>
      <description>Cross-national survey projects conduct surveys on representative samples of adult populations.How do the distributions of respondents’ age vary across surveys carried out in the same country in different years and different projects?
Like in a couple of previous posts (here, here and here) I use data from the Survey Data Recycling dataset (SDR) version 1, which includes selected harmonized variables from 22 cross-national survey projects. SDR only includes surveys that claim to have samples representative for adult populations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliability of survey estimates: Participation in demonstrations</title>
      <link>/post/sdr-demonstrations-multiplets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 17:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sdr-demonstrations-multiplets/</guid>
      <description>DataDifferences within country-yearsDifferences by groupsGenderAgeUrban/rural residenceEducationSampling schemeThe growth in cross-national survey projects in the last decades leads to situations when two or more surveys are carried out in the same country and the same year but in different projects, and contain overlapping sets of survey questions. Assuming that the surveys are based on representative samples - a claim that major cross-national survey projects typically make - it could be expected that estimates from surveys carried out in the same country and year are reasonably close.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiny app for exploring harmonized cross-national survey data (SDR v.1.0)</title>
      <link>/post/sdr-exploration-shiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 07:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sdr-exploration-shiny/</guid>
      <description>InstructionsReferences In the previous post I wrote about downloading and exploring the Survey Data Recycling (SDR), version 1 dataset, which consists of selected harmonized variables from 22 survey projects, 1966-2013.
The SDR project will develop a website for browsing, subsetting, downloading, and visualizing data from the SDR project. This website is currently under construction. Meanwhile, I made a Shiny app with basic functionalities of the future on-line browsing and subsetting tool (also serves as its mock-up): https://mkolczynska.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the dataset of survey datasets: Survey Data Recycling version 1</title>
      <link>/post/sdr-exploration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 15:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sdr-exploration/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionDownloading the SDR dataExploring SDR: availability of variables by projectExploring SDR: availability of variables with different formulationsIdentifying surveys containing selected variablesSubsetting the Master FileCountry coverage plotCombining data from different survey projects creates new opportunities for research, alas, at the cost of increased volume (obviously) and complexity of the data. The Survey Data Recycling project created a dataset with data from 22 international survey projects.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>