<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Political Participation on Marta Kołczyńska</title>
    <link>/tags/political-participation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Political Participation on Marta Kołczyńska</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018. Marta Kołczyńska</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 15:52:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/political-participation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Downloading country-level indicators on participation and economic inequality 2</title>
      <link>/post/participation-inequality-indices-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 15:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/participation-inequality-indices-2/</guid>
      <description>DataPackagesVarieties of Democracy (V-Dem): Dedicated packagePolyarchy: Semicolon delimited CSV file -&amp;gt; rioFreedom House: Excel file with by-year sheetsPolity IV: SPSS file -&amp;gt; rioDemocracy Barometer: Excel file with header in top rows -&amp;gt; rioThe Standardized World Income Inequality Database (SWIID): Plain CSV file -&amp;gt; rioWorld Bank’s World Development Indicators: Dedicated packageMerging all datasetsWriting to fileShortly after writing this post on importing datasets in different formats (CSV, XLS, XLSX, SAV) to R, I got the following comment:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downloading country-level indicators on participation and economic inequality</title>
      <link>/post/participation-inequality-indices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 13:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/participation-inequality-indices/</guid>
      <description>DataPackagesVarieties of Democracy (V-Dem): Dedicated packagePolyarchy: Semicolon delimited CSV fileFreedom House: Excel file with by-year sheetsPolity IV: SPSS fileDemocracy Barometer: Excel file with header in top rowsThe Standardized World Income Inequality Database (SWIID): Plain CSV fileWorld Bank’s World Development Indicators: Dedicated packageMerging all datasetsCountry graphsVariable graphsWriting to filewith Viktoriia Muliavka
Social and political scientists often need to put together datasets of country-level political, economic, and demographic variables with data from different sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voter shifts in parliamentary elections in Poland, 2007-2015</title>
      <link>/post/polpan-voting-alluvial-plots/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 11:32:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/polpan-voting-alluvial-plots/</guid>
      <description>How 2015 voters voted in 2007 and 2011How 2007 voters voted in 2011 and 2015About POLPANWhere did the current governing party get their votes from? Did supporters of the previous ruling party switch preferences or did they abstain from voting altogether? Cross-sectional datasets, such as one-off election polls, do not typically provide data to answer these questions. Panel studies, such as the Polish Panel Survey (POLPAN), do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Political participation patterns in Poland</title>
      <link>/post/ess-lca-participation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 16:13:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ess-lca-participation/</guid>
      <description>Political participation in PolandLatent class analysisThree types of participants: the Disengaged, Activists, and ProtestersRegion mapsI recently came across Jennifer Oser’s 2017 article in Social Indicators Research about “political tool kits”, i.e. profiles (or patterns) of participation in different political activities. Her general argument is that research on citizen participation would benefit from analyses of such participation patterns instead of (or at least in addition to) just looking at determinants of participation in single activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring the level and inequality of political participation with survey data</title>
      <link>/post/participation-inequality-ess/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 03:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/participation-inequality-ess/</guid>
      <description>Political participation in the ESSCountry levels of political participationInequality of political participationDemocracy indicatorsEconomic inequalityMatrix scatter plotsHow to measure political inequality? The Variaties of Democracy project (V-Dem) has a set of political equality indicators that capture the extent to which political power is distributed according to wealth and income, membership in a particular social group, gender or sexual orientation (cf. V-Dem Codebook v.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reliability of survey estimates: Participation in demonstrations</title>
      <link>/post/sdr-demonstrations-multiplets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 17:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sdr-demonstrations-multiplets/</guid>
      <description>DataDifferences within country-yearsDifferences by groupsGenderAgeUrban/rural residenceEducationSampling schemeThe growth in cross-national survey projects in the last decades leads to situations when two or more surveys are carried out in the same country and the same year but in different projects, and contain overlapping sets of survey questions. Assuming that the surveys are based on representative samples - a claim that major cross-national survey projects typically make - it could be expected that estimates from surveys carried out in the same country and year are reasonably close.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>