<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marta Kołczyńska</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Marta Kołczyńska</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018. Marta Kołczyńska</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 12:46:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dot plot challenge: Gender gap in voting in general elections in Europe</title>
      <link>/post/dot-plot-voting-ess/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 12:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/dot-plot-voting-ess/</guid>
      <description>Getting and reshaping the dataThe Dot PlotThe August edition of the Storytelling with Data challenge #SWDchallenge stars the dot plot. Here is a simple plot of the gender gap in voting in national elections using the most recent 8th Round of the European Social Survey, ESS.
Getting and reshaping the datalibrary(essurvey) # getting European Social Survey datalibrary(tidyverse) # data cleaning and reshapinglibrary(countrycode) # converting country codes to nameslibrary(ggplot2) # plotsWith the essurvey package the ESS data can be downloaded directly to R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiny app for exploring harmonized cross-national survey data (SDR v.1.0)</title>
      <link>/post/sdr-exploration-shiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 07:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sdr-exploration-shiny/</guid>
      <description>InstructionsReferences In the previous post I wrote about downloading and exploring the Survey Data Recycling (SDR), version 1.0 dataset, which consists of selected harmonized variables from 22 survey projects, 1966-2013.
The SDR project will develop a website for browsing, subsetting, downloading, and visualizing data from the SDR project. This website is currently under construction. Meanwhile, I made a Shiny app with basic functionalities of the future on-line browsing and subsetting tool (also serves as its mock-up): https://mkolczynska.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the dataset of survey datasets: Survey Data Recycling version 1.0</title>
      <link>/post/sdr-exploration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 15:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sdr-exploration/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionDownloading the SDR dataExploring SDR: availability of variables by projectExploring SDR: availability of variables with different formulationsIdentifying surveys containing selected variablesSubsetting the Master FileCountry coverage plottl;dr: Combining data from different survey projects creates new opportunities for research, alas, at the cost of increased volume (obviously) and complexity of the data. The Survey Data Recycling project created a dataset with data from 22 international survey projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISA World Congress 2018: Analysis of tweets</title>
      <link>/post/isa-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 15:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/isa-twitter/</guid>
      <description>Getting data from TwitterTweets over timeText analysisTweets by ISA Resesarch CommitteeThe International Sociological Association 19th World Congress of Sociology in Toronto (15-21 July) has received quite some Twitter coverage. Waiting to board the flight back to Warsaw, I wanted to take a look at these Twitter data and apply the newly acquired skills in text analysis (thanks to the Summer Institute for Computational Social Science, SICSS, Partner Site in Tvärminne and Helsinki, Finland).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Late start</title>
      <link>/post/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 13:19:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/first-post/</guid>
      <description>This blog is going to be mostly about my adventures with R, primarily using survey data, and usually somewhat related to my social science interests; for the fun of it, to share code and hopefully get feedback.
How it all started General law of academia: The capacity for generating ideas is greater than the capacity of developing ideas into papers.
So why write a blog and not keep a diary or a plain text file sitting safely on your hard drive, kochanie?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a post-doctoral researcher at the Institute of Philosophy and Sociology, Polish Academy of Sciences, and a recent Ph.D. graduate from the Department of Sociology, The Ohio State University. My research interests include comparative analyses of political attitudes and behavior across nations and over time, as well as the methodology of comparative research, in particular cross-national surveys.
My full CV
Research interests  Political attitudes and behavior
 Quantitative methods for comparative and cross-national research</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>e-mail:
mkolczynska(at)ifispan.waw.pl
kolczynska.1(at)osu.edu</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description>Political Inequality I&amp;rsquo;m currently working as a post-doc in the project Political Voice and Economic Inequality across Nations and Time led by dr. Joshua K. Dubrow. In this project I use my knowledge of cross-national surveys and methodology to investigate how economic and educational inequality translates into political marginalization – a topic of renewed relevance in the current turbulent times. I develop country-level measures of political inequality using data from various sources: survey data, administrative records, event data, and others.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>