<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marta Kołczyńska</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Marta Kołczyńska</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018. Marta Kołczyńska</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 19:19:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>/post/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 19:19:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/first-post/</guid>
      <description>Step 1. Install R Probably the most useful thing I learned in grad school is that there is an R package for everything, including cocktails, getting colors from Dutch paintings, and - obviously - blogging.
Step 2. Find a tutorial My favorite quote from blogdown: Creating Websites with R Markdown by Yihui Xie, Amber Thomas, Alison Presmanes Hill:
 If you do not understand HTML, CSS, or JavaScript, and have no experience with Hugo themes or templates, it may take you about 10 minutes to get started with your new website &amp;hellip; if you do have the knowledge and experience (and desire to highly customize your site), it may take you several days to get started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a post-doctoral researcher at the Institute of Philosophy and Sociology, Polish Academy of Sciences.
Full CV</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>e-mail:
mkolczynska(at)gmail.com
kolczynska.1(at)osu.edu</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description>Research Interests Democratization, Education, Economic Inequality, Survey data harmonization, Quantitative methods for comparative and cross-national survey research; Data visualization and database management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/first-rmarkdown-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/first-rmarkdown-post/</guid>
      <description>R MarkdownThis is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars)## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>