<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marta Kołczyńska</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Marta Kołczyńska</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018. Marta Kołczyńska</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 15:24:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ISA World Congress 2018: Analysis of tweets</title>
      <link>/post/isa-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 15:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/isa-twitter/</guid>
      <description>The International Sociological Association 19th World Congress of Sociology in Toronto, (15-21 July) has received quite some Twitter coverage. Waiting to board the flight back to Warsaw, I wanted to take a look at these Twitter data and apply the newly acquired skills in text analysis (thanks to the Summer Institute for Computational Social Science, SICSS, Partner Site in Tvärminne and Helsinki, Finland).
A few years ago my colleagues from the Polish Academy of Sciences and I wrote a paper about the inequality in national representation at ISA events (congresses and fora) 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Late start</title>
      <link>/post/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 13:19:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/first-post/</guid>
      <description>This blog is going to be mostly about my adventures with R, primarily using survey data, and usually somewhat related to my social science interests; for the fun of it, to share code and hopefully get feedback.
How it all started General law of academia: The capacity for generating ideas is greater than the capacity of developing ideas into papers.
So why write a blog and not keep a diary or a plain text file sitting safely on your hard drive, kochanie?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a post-doctoral researcher at the Institute of Philosophy and Sociology, Polish Academy of Sciences, and a recent Ph.D. graduate from the Department of Sociology, The Ohio State University. My research interests include comparative analyses of political attitudes and behavior across nations and over time, as well as the methodology of comparative research, in particular cross-national surveys.
My full CV
Research interests  Political attitudes and behavior
 Quantitative methods for comparative and cross-national research</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>e-mail:
mkolczynska(at)ifispan.waw.pl
kolczynska.1(at)osu.edu</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description>Political Inequality I&amp;rsquo;m currently working as a post-doc in the project Political Voice and Economic Inequality across Nations and Time led by dr. Joshua K. Dubrow. In this project I use my knowledge of cross-national surveys and methodology to investigate how economic and educational inequality translates into political marginalization – a topic of renewed relevance in the current turbulent times. I develop country-level measures of political inequality using data from various sources: survey data, administrative records, event data, and others.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>