<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Marta Kołczyńska</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Marta Kołczyńska</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018. Marta Kołczyńska</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 15:24:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ISA World Congress 2018: Analysis of tweets</title>
      <link>/post/isa-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 15:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/isa-twitter/</guid>
      <description>The International Sociological Association World Congress 19th Congress of Sociology in Toronto has received quite some Twitter coverage. Waiting to board the flight back to Warsaw, I wanted to take a look at these Twitter data and apply the newly acquired skills in text analysis (thanks to the Summer Institute for Computational Social Science, SICSS, Partner Site in Tvärminne and Helsinki, Finland).
A few years ago my colleagues from the Polish Academy of Sciences and I wrote a paper about the inequality in national representation at ISA events (congresses and fora) 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Late start</title>
      <link>/post/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 13:19:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/first-post/</guid>
      <description>This blog is going to be mostly about my adventures with R, primarily using survey data, and usually somewhat related to my social science interests; for the fun of it, to share code and hopefully get feedback.
How it all started General law of academia: The capacity for generating ideas is greater than the capacity of developing ideas into papers.
So why write a blog and not keep a diary or a plain text file sitting safely on your hard drive, kochanie?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>