<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Marta Kołczyńska</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Marta Kołczyńska</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018. Marta Kołczyńska</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 15:41:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the dataset of survey datasets: Survey Data Recycling version 1.0</title>
      <link>/post/sdr-exploration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 15:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sdr-exploration/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionDownloading the SDR dataExploring SDR: availability of variables by projectExploring SDR: availability of variables with different formulationsIdentifying surveys containing selected variablesSubsetting the Master Filetl;dr: Combining data from different survey projects creates new opportunities for research, alas, at the cost of increased volume (obviously) and complexity of the data. The Survey Data Recycling project created a dataset with data from 22 international survey projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISA World Congress 2018: Analysis of tweets</title>
      <link>/post/isa-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 15:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/isa-twitter/</guid>
      <description>Getting data from TwitterTweets over timeText analysisTweets by ISA Resesarch CommitteeThe International Sociological Association 19th World Congress of Sociology in Toronto (15-21 July) has received quite some Twitter coverage. Waiting to board the flight back to Warsaw, I wanted to take a look at these Twitter data and apply the newly acquired skills in text analysis (thanks to the Summer Institute for Computational Social Science, SICSS, Partner Site in Tvärminne and Helsinki, Finland).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Late start</title>
      <link>/post/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 13:19:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/first-post/</guid>
      <description>This blog is going to be mostly about my adventures with R, primarily using survey data, and usually somewhat related to my social science interests; for the fun of it, to share code and hopefully get feedback.
How it all started General law of academia: The capacity for generating ideas is greater than the capacity of developing ideas into papers.
So why write a blog and not keep a diary or a plain text file sitting safely on your hard drive, kochanie?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>