<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sdr on Marta Kołczyńska</title>
    <link>/tags/sdr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sdr on Marta Kołczyńska</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018. Marta Kołczyńska</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 13:32:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/sdr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiny App for exploring harmonized survey data (Survey Data Recycling v.1.0)</title>
      <link>/post/sdr-exploration-shiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 13:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sdr-exploration-shiny/</guid>
      <description>My previous post was about downloading and exploring the Survey Data Recycling (SDR), version 1.0 dataset, which consists of selected harmonized variables from 22 survey projects, 1966-2013.
The SDR project will develop a website for browsing, subsetting, downloading, and visualizing data from the SDR project. This website is currently under construction. Meanwhile, basic functionalities of the future on-line browsing and subsetting tool are available here: https://mkolczynska.shinyapps.io/sdr_data_browser/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the dataset of survey datasets: Survey Data Recycling version 1.0</title>
      <link>/post/sdr-exploration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 13:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sdr-exploration/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr: Combining data from different survey projects creates new opportunities for research, but the comes at a cost of increased complexity of the data.
Cross-national survey projects are the standard data source for cross-national quantitative research in sociology. Such projects typically have similar questionnaires in all national surveys and - to a greater or lesser extent - standardized methodologies as well as documentation and reporting. Due to logistical challenges and interests of project leaders, cross-national survey projects remain limited in country and time coverage, which restricts prevents analalyses on a global scale.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>